In this video, I'd like
在这个视频中 我想要
(字幕整理：中国海洋大学 黄海广,haiguang2000@qq.com )
to talk about how to initialize
讨论一下如何初始化
K-means and more importantly, this will
K均值聚类方法 更重要的是 这将
lead into a discussion of
引导我们讨论
how to make K-means avoid local optima as well.
如何避开局部最优来构建K均值聚类方法
Here's the K-means clustering algorithm
这是一个我们之前讨论过的
that we talked about earlier.
K均值聚类算法
One step that we never really
其中我们之前没有
talked much about was this step
讨论得太多的是这一步
of how you randomly initialize the cluster centroids.
如何初始化聚类中心这一步
There are few different ways that
有几种不同的方法
one can imagine using to randomly
可以用来随机
initialize the cluster centroids.
初始化聚类中心
But, it turns out that
但是 事实证明
there is one method that is
有一种方法比其他
much more recommended than most
大多数可能考虑到的方法
of the other options one might think about.
更加被推荐
So, let me tell you about
接下来就告诉你这个
that option since it's what often seems to work best.
方法 因为它可能是效果最好的一种方法
Here's how I usually initialize my cluster centroids.
这里展示了我通常是如何初始化我的聚类中心的
When running K-means, you should have
当运行K均值方法时 你需要有
the number of cluster centroids, K,
一个聚类中心数值K
set to be less than the
K值要比
number of training examples M. It
训练样本的数量m小
would be really weird to run
如果运行一个
K-means with a number
K均值
of cluster centroids that's, you know,
聚类中心数值
equal or greater than the number of examples you have, right?
等于或者大于样本数的K均值聚类方法会很奇怪
So the way I
我通常用来
usually initialize K-means is,
初始化K均值聚类的方法是
I would randomly pick k training
随机挑选K个训练
examples. So, and, what
样本 然后
I do is then set Mu1
我要做的是设定μ1
of MuK equal to these k examples.
到μk让它们等于这个K个样本
Let me show you a concrete example.
让我展示一个具体的例子
Lets say that k is
我们假设 K
equal to 2 and so
等于2 那么
on this example on the right let's say I want to find two clusters.
就在这个例子的右边 假设我们想找到两个聚类
So, what I'm going to
那么为了初始化
do in order to initialize
聚类中心
my cluster centroids is, I'm
我要做的是
going to randomly pick a couple examples.
随机挑选几个样本
And let's say, I pick
比如说 我挑选了
this one and I pick that one.
这个和这个
And the way I'm going
我要
to initialize my cluster centroids
初始化聚类中心的方法
is, I'm just going to initialize
就是 我只需要初始化
my cluster centroids to be right on top of those examples.
聚类中心正确的样本中
So that's my first cluster centroid
因此这是我的第一个聚类中心
and that's my second cluster centroid, and
这是我的第二个聚类中心
that's one random initialization of K-means.
这就是一个随机初始化K均值聚类的方法
The one I drew looks like a particularly good one.
刚刚我画的看上去是相当不错的一个例子
And sometimes I might get less
但是有时候我可能不会
lucky and maybe I'll end
那么幸运 也许我最后
up picking that as my first
会挑选到 这一个是我第一个
random initial example, and that as my second one.
挑选到的初始化样本 而这是第二个
And here I'm picking two examples because k equals 2.
这就是我所挑选的两个样本 因为K等于2
Some we have randomly picked two
我们随机挑选了两个
training examples and if
训练样本 如果
I chose those two then I'll
我挑选这两个 那么我
end up with, may be
结果就有可能得到
this as my first cluster
这个是第一个聚类
centroid and that as
中心 这个是
my second initial location of the cluster centroid.
第二个聚类中心
So, that's how you can randomly
这就是如何随机
initialize the cluster centroids.
初始化聚类中心
And so at initialization, your
因此在初始化时 你的第一个
first cluster centroid Mu1 will
聚类中心μ1
be equal to x(i) for
等于x(i)
some randomly value of i and
对于某一个随机的i值
Mu2 will be equal to x(j)
μ2等于x(j)
for some different randomly chosen value
对应另一个随机选择的不同的
of j and so on,
j的值 等等
if you have more clusters and more cluster centroid.
如果你有更多的聚类和更多的聚类中心的话
And sort of the side common.
通常
I should say that in the
应该这样说
earlier video where I first
前面的视频中 在我第一次
illustrated K-means with the animation.
用动画说明K均值方法时
In that set of slides.
在那些幻灯片中
Only for the purpose of illustration.
仅仅是为了说明
I actually used a different
我实际上用了一种不同的
method of initialization for my cluster centroids.
初始化方法来初始化聚类中心
But the method described on
而这张幻灯片中描述的方法
this slide, this is really the recommended way.
是真正被推荐的方法
And the way that you should probably use, when you implement K-means.
这种方法在你实现K均值聚类的时候可能会用到
So, as they suggested perhaps
根据推荐
by these two illustrations on the right.
也许通过这右边的两个图
You might really guess that K-means
你可能会猜到K均值方法
can end up converging to
最终可能会得到
different solutions depending on
不同的结果 取决于
exactly how the clusters
聚类簇的初始化方法
were initialized, and so, depending on the random initialization.
因此也就取决于随机的初始化
K-means can end up at different solutions.
K均值方法最后可能得到不同的结果
And, in particular, K-means can actually end up at local optima.
尤其是如果K均值方法落在局部最优的时候
If you're given the data sale like this.
如果给你一些数据 比如说这些
Well, it looks like, you know, there
这看起来好像有
are three clusters, and so,
3个聚类 那么
if you run K-means and if
如果你运行K均值方法 如果
it ends up at a good
它最后得到一个
local optima this might be
局部最优 这可能是
really the global optima, you might end up with that cluster ring.
真正的全局最优 你可能会得到这样的聚类结果
But if you had a particularly
但是如果你运气特别
unlucky, random initialization, K-means
不好 随机初始化 K均值方法
can also get stuck at different
也可能会卡在不同的
local optima. So, in
局部最优上面 因此在
this example on the left
有变的这个例子中
it looks like this blue cluster has captured
看上去蓝色的聚类捕捉到了
a lot of points of the left and then the they were on the green clusters
左边的很多点 而且它们在绿色的聚类中
each is captioned on the relatively small number of points.
每一个聚类都捕捉到了相对较少的点
And so, this corresponds to
这与
a bad local optima because it
不好的局部最优相对应 因为
has basically taken these two
它基本上是基于这两个
clusters and used them into
聚类的 并且它们
1 and furthermore, has
进一步合并成了1个聚类 而
split the second cluster into
把第二个聚类分割成了
two separate sub-clusters like
两个像这样的小的聚类
so, and it has also
它也把
taken the second cluster and
第二个聚类
split it into two
分割成了两个
separate sub-clusters like so, and
分别的像这样的小聚类簇
so, both of these
这两个
examples on the lower
右下方的例子
right correspond to different local
对应与K均值方法的
optima of K-means and in fact,
不同的局部最优 实际上
in this example here,
这里的这个例子
the cluster, the red cluster
这个红色的簇
has captured only a single optima example.
只捕捉到了一个最好的样本
And the term local
这个局部
optima, by the way, refers
最优项 顺便提一下 代表
to local optima of this
这个失真函数J
distortion function J, and
的局部最优
what these solutions on the
这些在右下方的解
lower left, what these local
这些局部
optima correspond to is
最优所对应的是
really solutions where K-means
真正的K均值方法
has gotten stuck to the local
所遇到的局部
optima and it's not doing
最优 且
a very good job minimizing this
通过最小化这个
distortion function J. So,
失真函数J并不能得到很好的结果 因此
if you're worried about K-means getting
如果你担心K均值方法会遇到
stuck in local optima, if
局部最优的问题 如果
you want to increase the odds
你想提高
of K-means finding the best
K均值方法找到最
possible clustering, like that shown
有可能的聚类的几率的话
on top here, what we
就像这上面所展示的 我们能做的
can do, is try multiple, random initializations.
是尝试多次 随机的初始化
So, instead of just initializing K-means
而不是仅仅初始化一次K均值方法
once and hopping that that
就希望它会得到
works, what we can do
很好的结果 我们能做的是
is, initialize K-means lots of
初始化K均值很多次
times and run K-means lots of
并运行K均值方法很多次
times, and use that to
通过多次尝试
try to make sure we get
来保证我们最终能得到
as good a solution, as
一个足够好的结果 一个
good a local or global optima as possible.
尽可能局部或全局最优的结果
Concretely, here's how you could go about doing that.
具体地 这就是你能够做的
Let's say, I decide to run
假如我决定运行
K-meanss a hundred times
K均值方法一百次
so I'll execute this loop
那么我就需要执行这个循环
a hundred times and it's
100次
fairly typical a number of
这是一个相当典型的次数数字
times when came to will be
有时会是
something from 50 up to may be 1000.
从50到1000之间
So, let's say you decide to say K-means one hundred times.
假设说有决定运行K均值方法100次
So what that means is that
那么这就意味这
we would randomnly initialize K-means.
我们要随机初始化K均值方法
And for each of
对于这些
these one hundred random intializations
100次随机初始化的每一次
we would run K-means and
我们需要运行K均值方法
that would give us a set
我们会得到一系列
of clusteringings, and a set of cluster
聚类结果 和一系列聚类
centroids, and then we
中心 之后
would then compute the distortion J,
我们可以计算失真函数J
that is compute this cause function on
用我们得到的
the set of cluster assignments
这些聚类结果
and cluster centroids that we got.
和聚类中心来计算这样一个结果函数
Finally, having done this whole procedure a hundred times.
最后 完成整个过程100次之后
You will have a hundred different ways
你会得到这个100种
of clustering the data and then
聚类数据的这些方法
finally what you do
最后你要做的是
is all of these hundred
在所有这100种
ways you have found of clustering the data,
用于聚类的方法中
just pick one, that gives us the lowest cost.
选取能够给我们代价最小的一个
That gives us the lowest distortion.
给我们最低畸变值的一个
And it turns out that
事实证明
if you are running K-means with
如果你运行K均值方法时
a fairly small number of
所用的聚类数相当小
clusters , so you know if the number
那么如果聚类
of clusters is anywhere from
数是从
two up to maybe 10 -
2到10之间的任何数的话
then doing multiple random initializations
做多次的随机初始化
can often, can sometimes make
通常能够保证
sure that you find a better local optima.
你能有一个较好的局部最优解
Make sure you find the better clustering data.
保证你能找到更好的聚类数据
But if K is very large, so, if
但是如果K非常大的话 如果
K is much greater than 10,
K比10大很多
certainly if K were, you
当然如果K是
know, if you were trying to
如果你尝试去
find hundreds of clusters, then,
找到成百上千个聚类 那么
having multiple random initializations is
有多个随机初始化就
less likely to make a huge difference
不太可能会有太大的影响
and there is a much
更有
higher chance that your first
可能你的第一次
random initialization will give
随机初始化就会给
you a pretty decent solution already
你相当好的结果
and doing, doing multiple random
做多次随机
initializations will probably give
初始化可能会给
you a slightly better solution but, but maybe not that much.
你稍微好一点的结果 但是不会好太多
But it's really in the regime of where
但是在这样一个
you have a relatively small number
聚类数相对较小的体系里
of clusters, especially if you
特别是如果你
have, maybe 2 or 3
有2个或者3个
or 4 clusters that random
或者4个聚类的话 随机
initialization could make a huge difference in terms of
初始化会有较大的影响
making sure you do a good
可以保证你在
job minimizing the distortion
最小化失真函数的时候得到一个很小的值
function and giving you a good clustering.
并且能得到一个很好的聚类结果
So, that's K-means
这就是随机初始化
with random initialization.
的K均值初始化方法
If you're trying to learn a
如果你尝试学习一种
clustering with a relatively small
聚类数目相对较小
number of clusters, 2, 3,
的聚类方法 如2,3
4, 5, maybe, 6, 7, using
4,5,6,7 用
multiple random initializations can
多次随机初始化
sometimes, help you find much better clustering of the data.
有时能够帮助你找到更好的数据聚类结果
But, even if you are learning a large number of clusters, the initialization, the random
但是 尽管你有很多聚类数目 初始化
initialization method that I describe here.
我在这里介绍的随机初始化
That should give K-means a
它会给K均值方法一个
reasonable starting point to start
合理的起始点来开始
from for finding a good set of clusters.
并找到一个好的聚类结果 【教育无边界字幕组】翻译: 星星之火 校对/审核:所罗门捷列夫